[
  {
    "question": "1. What is a stack?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) A linear data structure with FIFO behavior",
      "b) A hierarchical data structure",
      "c) A linear data structure with variable capacity",
      "d) A linear data structure with LIFO (Last In, First Out) behavior"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. Which operation adds an element to the top of the stack?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
    "options": [
      "a) push",
      "b) pop",
      "c) top",
      "d) dequeue"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Which operation removes the top element from the stack?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
    "options": [
      "a) push",
      "b) pop",
      "c) top",
      "d) dequeue"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Which of the following is not a common implementation of a stack?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) Linked List",
      "b) Array",
      "c) Dynamic Array",
      "d) Binary Tree"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What is the time complexity of push and pop operations in a stack implemented using an array?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
    "options": [
      "a) O(1) for both push and pop",
      "b) O(n) for push and O(1) for pop",
      "c) O(log n) for both push and pop",
      "d) O(n) for both push and pop"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What is a LIFO data structure?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
    "options": [
      "a) A data structure with FIFO behavior",
      "b) A data structure with variable capacity",
      "c) A data structure with LIFO behavior",
      "d) A data structure with fixed capacity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. Which operation is used to retrieve the top element of the stack without removing it?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
    "options": [
      "a) push",
      "b) pop",
      "c) top",
      "d) dequeue"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. What is the maximum number of elements that can be stored in a stack with fixed capacity?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) Limited by the capacity of the stack",
      "b) Unlimited",
      "c) Double the capacity of the stack",
      "d) Equal to the capacity of the stack plus one"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Which operation is used to check if a stack is empty?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) push",
      "b) pop",
      "c) top",
      "d) isEmpty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. Which data structure is often used to implement a stack with variable capacity?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
    "options": [
      "a) Dynamic Array",
      "b) Linked List",
      "c) Circular Buffer",
      "d) Array"
    ]
  }
]